Hello everyone, welcome to Model Kit
Stuff. My name is Jason and today we've
got a product review for you. Clear tint
masking magic from Deluxe Materials.
What's that all about then?
Yes, welcome along everyone. It's
another product review. So, masking
magic, what would you need a masking
fluid for? Well, many of us who've been
modeling for a long time grew up with a
product called Maskol by Humbrol, which
is like a
a liquid latex that you put on clear
parts so that you don't paint over them.
Um
and then more recently for clear parts
people have used
these masking tapes for masking, but
quite a lot of them these days require
you to mask in the middle anyway and
they just have the outer where you've
got a shaped
glass dome. But, you also might want to
use masking for things like camouflage
schemes,
masking off areas of a vehicle while
you're touching up or painting some
detail parts. It has lots and lots of um
possibilities. You can mask plastic, you
can mask metal, you can pretty much mask
any hard surface. Although on wood you'd
want to make sure that wood is sealed
and cleared cuz it can stick in the
grain. Um
So,
yeah,
this is a product I've not tried before
so we're going to give it a go.
I I came recently to my Maskol I've not
used for a little while and it was set
hard so I thought let's try something
different. Now the instructions tell me
I need to give this a good shake. So,
that's what we're going to do.
Um the bottle looks about 3/4 full.
Um it tells us on here that we've got 40
g of product.
So, we've given it a good shake
and I've got these
masking sets which came off eBay. Let's
see if we can get the camera to focus.
There we go. And the problem I have with
them is actually the masks are a bit
small and you can see the glass.
So, they don't actually work and
I'm not happy with this one either. It
it doesn't quite reach across.
Uh so, I'm actually going to try this
masking product instead of the paint
masks. So, we're going to get rid of the
paint masks. That was a waste of time,
wasn't it? And
get straight into our masking fluid.
So, with the top taken off, what we've
got is
a fairly
gloopy, thick
clear product that's
reminds me very much of Maskol. Um the
difference is this is going to dry
translucent rather than solid pink.
So, I'm hoping that we're going to be
able to see
where we are. Why is that important? I
can hear you thinking. Well, on clear
parts possibly not, but if you're
masking detail cuz you're going to be
painting round it you might want to see
what's beneath it. So,
that's what stirred my interest in this
product.
Now, I've got to say because it's thick
and gloopy it's quite easy to get right
up to the edge.
So, I like that about it.
And it's not drying and I'm pulling off
like Maskol sometimes does. You can see
I'm able to
go back over it
and it's not pulling.
So, the drying time on the bottle is
recommended at 2 to 3 hours.
So, that gives you loads and loads of
time
to get this right up to the edges where
you want it.
Yeah, that's gone down really well
actually. That's been
very easy to do.
So, let's try a little bit more. So,
I'll take a bit more out of the cap.
I'm just going to put the cap back on
for now. I think with these sort of
products it's always best to keep the
air out as long as you can.
So, this is quite a curved
It's a dome-shaped piece of glass.
Do you know what? There is so much
control of this product.
Okay, I'm just going to put a little bit
more on just
about embraces. I'm going to take some
from inside the bottle.
Yeah, so that's no different than what's
in the cap. It's not like we had some
dried stuff in the cap.
So, I put it on quite thick, but it
looks like
it already looks where it's drying
to be quite clear.
Don't know why my uh
camera's not wanting to focus today.
So, I just want to make sure that I'm
right up to the edges. I think I am.
So, using a paint mask when I have
finished with the with the mask and the
painting and I remove the mask
inevitably I have some clean up around
the edges where the mask hasn't quite
perfectly fitted and that's always
bothered me, but it still saved me a lot
of time on cutting my own masks. That's
why I use them. But, I'm now wondering
if actually it's quicker for me to just
use masking fluid.
Now, one of the reasons that I sort of
moved away from using masking fluid was
the lack of control
and the fact that it dried really
quickly
meant that you couldn't manipulate it
and you're pulling it off. Uh and it was
almost more work
putting the masking on than
the time it saved you cleaning up. So,
this is going on really really quickly
and I'm proving to myself here
that I can get right up to the edges.
And that I don't need to put tons on.
So, quite often with Maskol cuz you're
pulling bits away you are putting more
liquid on.
I don't appear to have that issue with
this product.
Yeah, that is quicker. That is quicker
than masking with
masking tape.
And I think that's done a better job.
So, when we come to remove it I'll have
less clean up in theory. So,
uh yeah, I really like that.
So, the final test of our masking magic
is actually unmasking.
Um
these two masks
if I pick them up you can see the
masking fluid still visible.
Um they have been on about a fortnight
and they've had two coats of
well, two different colors of enamel
paint go over them. Um the gray was
passed over at least twice, the green
probably about the same. So, you're
you're looking at a minimum of four
coats of enamel paint which has been
hardened on here for about 4 days now.
So, I want to see how it behaves, how it
comes off. I mean this is for me
ultimate test territory for this. Um
previously with masking fluids I found
Maskol for example that, you know,
because they're basically a liquid
latex it's all stretching, it snaps off
and you've got bits and it's quite a
messy business. So, I want to see what
this is like.
Um it's certainly a lot thinner and a
lot more even. You could even forget
you've got it on if you weren't careful.
So,
it's behaved differently going down.
Will it behave differently going up?
Well,
I've managed to lift the corner.
So, it has ripped there, but I've
managed to collect that rip.
Oh, wow. That is pretty much come out in
one piece.
Uh I mean, that's unheard of.
That That has done a really, really good
job.
Um let's just have a look. I've got
one little piece there that has
ripped off.
Cuz the liquid is a lot finer,
it's uh gone into the cracks a little
bit. I'm not sure is that a bit of
No, that's not masking fluid. That's a
bit of window that I didn't quite get
covered off. But, look at that. I mean,
look at how crisp that is.
That is really, really good. Let's do
this other larger one. Now, this one is
slightly domed.
Um and we had a little
um interesting shape in the corner,
which you should be able to see there.
Um
So, that's the corner I'm going to start
lifting it from.
Obviously being very careful here with
the uh
the tweezers.
Just gently peeling it back
until I've got an edge I can grab.
But, it's actually pulling away really,
really easily. It's not taking any
effort. I'm not having to sort of dig
into it or anything.
Wow, look at that.
Again, it's come off in one continuous
piece.
I am extremely impressed with that. This
is one of the best products I've tested
in a long time.
So,
I do have a tiny fleck of paint.
Just a tiny, tiny fleck where I didn't
get the liquid on
and cover it. Can you just about see
that in the light there? It's tiny.
It'll come off dead easily.
But, it's lovely, absolutely lovely.
That
That is by far the best performing
masking liquid I've ever used. So, there
you go.
Deluxe Materials Clear Tint Masking
Magic.
Um
I actually think this is the best
masking product I've ever used. I'm
very, very happy with it. So, uh yeah,
this is going to be my masking solution
um
of choice going forward. And to be
honest, you can apply it with such
accuracy that I probably don't need to
be buying um
uh
pre-cut masking masks. I can just go in
with this stuff.
Um yeah, I'm deeply impressed. So, there
you go. I hope that was useful
uh and interesting. Clear Tint Masking
Magic from Deluxe Materials. Um
Really great product. I've enjoyed using
it, and I've had very, very good
results. You've seen all of those. So,
um until the next time I see you, you
enjoy your modeling. And if you don't
want to miss future product reviews,
tool reviews, don't forget to hit the
subscribe button.
Bye for now.